<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Uncategorized &#8211; Revely Microsystems</title>
	<atom:link href="./index.html" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>./../../../index.html</link>
	<description>Revely Microsystem - the home of Growver and VoltWerks</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2019 23:09:07 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.10</generator>

<image>
	<url>./../../../wp-content/uploads/2018/05/cropped-Revely-Logo-with-name-square-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Uncategorized &#8211; Revely Microsystems</title>
	<link>./../../../index.html</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>The VoltWerks store is closing</title>
		<link>./../../../2018/06/05/the-voltwerks-store-is-closing/index.html</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Jun 2018 22:49:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[jaguy]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=1999</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>VoltWerks power supplies were launched in 2014 on Kickstarter. Since then we’ve shipped many hundreds of units to customers all around the world.  Although VoltWerks is still unique and has [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2018/06/05/the-voltwerks-store-is-closing/index.html">The VoltWerks store is closing</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Revely Microsystems</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>VoltWerks power supplies were launched in 2014 on Kickstarter. Since then we’ve shipped many hundreds of units to customers all around the world.  Although VoltWerks is still unique and has a loyal following, there’s not enough volume to justify another full-scale production build. The VoltWerks online store will close June 12, 2018.</p>
<p>There’s the possibility of limited quantities available for purchase after that date. Use the Revely Microsystems contact form if you’re interested.</p>
<p>To the hundreds of VoltWerks customers &#8211; thank you!</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2018/06/05/the-voltwerks-store-is-closing/index.html">The VoltWerks store is closing</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Revely Microsystems</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Growver: The Story as of July 2016</title>
		<link>./../../../2016/07/05/hello-world/index.html</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2016 00:59:32 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[jaguy]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=1</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>It’s coming up on 1 year since Growver was featured on ‘Make Me a Millionaire Inventor’ so I figured this was a great time for a run-through on the Growver [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2016/07/05/hello-world/index.html">Growver: The Story as of July 2016</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Revely Microsystems</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It’s coming up on 1 year since Growver was featured on ‘Make Me a Millionaire Inventor’ so I figured this was a great time for a run-through on the Growver story so far.</p>
<p>As a homeowner it hadn’t taken me long to figure out that my lawn sprinkler system wasted a lot of water, was costly to maintain, and basically did a poor job of keeping my grass alive. After years of looking at alternatives, it became clear that effective irrigation requires carrying water and placing it exactly where it&#8217;s needed. So, in May 2014, Growver development became my full-time job.</p>
<p>Since no-one had built a lawn watering robot before, I was starting from scratch. By the time I started talking with the producers of Make Me A Millionaire Inventor in early 2015, I’d built both hose-connected and tank-based Growver designs. During filming of the show, Michael and Martin at Blue Fish took my second generation prototype and transformed it into something that looks, moves and waters like a real product. I also got to take the new Growver design door-to-door in the LA area, getting real feedback from homeowners in an area that’s facing a massive water crisis. Feedback was very positive – I was on to something big!</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-1959" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2018/05/Generations-1-1024x576.png" alt="" width="640" height="360" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2018/05/Generations-1-1024x576.png 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2018/05/Generations-1-300x169.png 300w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2018/05/Generations-1-768x432.png 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2018/05/Generations-1.png 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" /></p>
<p>The highlight of the Make Me A Millionaire Inventor show is, of course, the pitch. I thought my pitch went very well and apparently so did the investor. Check out the show on CNBC if you haven’t already to follow the story and get the details!</p>
<p>Investor funding was critical to moving the design forward and into initial production and field testing. There are more development costs, as well as testing and expensive tooling. Unfortunately, up to this point, there’s been no outside money for Growver.</p>
<p>In February 2016, with funds running critically low, I decided to try funding Growver through a Kickstarter campaign. My first choice was to Kickstart the Make-Me-A-Millionaire-Inventor design. But due to the tooling costs and timeline, I had to go with a simple, hose-connected concept. The Kickstarter generated considerable interest but fell short – everyone wanted a fully automated hose-less that looked like the one on TV!</p>
<p>Today Growver development continues, though on a very constrained budget. Importantly, there’s some really cool technology that will let Growver install quickly and move autonomously around any lawn.</p>
<p>July 2016</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2016/07/05/hello-world/index.html">Growver: The Story as of July 2016</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Revely Microsystems</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How do you make the perfect irrigation system?</title>
		<link>./../../../2016/05/04/how-do-you-make-the-perfect-irrigation-system/index.html</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 00:42:46 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[jaguy]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=1995</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>If you have an unlimited water supply then watering a lawn is easy. Take some pipe, a few sprinklers, create large zones and blast away. Water as much and as [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2016/05/04/how-do-you-make-the-perfect-irrigation-system/index.html">How do you make the perfect irrigation system?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Revely Microsystems</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>If you have an unlimited water supply then watering a lawn is easy. Take some pipe, a few sprinklers, create large zones and blast away. Water as much and as often as you like until every square foot is a brilliant green.</p>
<p>In fact, until quite recently, the unlimited water scenario was essentially the reality of many urban areas. But now with drought, tapped-out aquifers, urban growth, aging utility infrastructure, and increased awareness of environmental sustainability, a brute force approach to watering is archaic (some would say lawns themselves are archaic – that’s a great topic for future discussion).</p>
<p>More recently, trends to smaller zones, smart controllers, and sensors can all help save water.  The problem is that, fundamentally, water is still flowing through pipes that leak and sprinklers that waste a lot of water. So now, just like gardens, we’re back to hand-watering lawns. Frustratingly, even for a small lawn, that takes hours! And that’s exactly where Growver comes in.</p>
<p><img class="alignnone wp-image-1996" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Lawn-Sprinkler-Maze.jpg" alt="" width="391" height="197" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Lawn-Sprinkler-Maze.jpg 800w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Lawn-Sprinkler-Maze-300x151.jpg 300w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Lawn-Sprinkler-Maze-768x387.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 391px) 100vw, 391px" /></p>
<p>What would the perfect irrigation system look like? That’s the question that started Growver development and naturally, this is something I still think about a lot.</p>
<p>Most in-ground irrigation systems use the same pipe-in-ground and sprinklers for both lawns and gardens, but it’s far from ideal for either situation.</p>
<p>For performance and water saving, Drip Irrigation is widely regarded as the way to go for gardens, especially if the time and money is invested to properly install and adjust the drip emitters for each plant. But unfortunately common feedback is that drip systems work great for a few years, but eventually suffer from hard-to-locate leaks, breaks in the fairly fragile piping, and root fibers entering emitters. Maintenance costs are high, and often result in replacing, rather than repairing, large sections of a system.</p>
<p>So now we’re back to hand watering of gardens. It’s very efficient, inexpensive, and dependable. Relaxing too, but only if you have the time, state-of-mind, and never leave town. For everyone else, I’m working to find a simple, reliable robotic solution to garden watering.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2016/05/04/how-do-you-make-the-perfect-irrigation-system/index.html">How do you make the perfect irrigation system?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Revely Microsystems</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Do Smart Sprinkler Controllers Save Water?</title>
		<link>./../../../2015/06/04/do-smart-sprinkler-controllers-save-water/index.html</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2015 00:17:13 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[jaguy]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=1976</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>A recent article in the San Jose Mercury News covered the trend towards smart sprinkler controls. Smart sprinkler controllers promise to reduce water use for most users by over 30%. Now [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2015/06/04/do-smart-sprinkler-controllers-save-water/index.html">Do Smart Sprinkler Controllers Save Water?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Revely Microsystems</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignnone wp-image-1977" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2018/06/SprinklerController.jpg" alt="" width="361" height="247" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2018/06/SprinklerController.jpg 600w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2018/06/SprinklerController-300x205.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 361px) 100vw, 361px" /></p>
<p>A recent article in the San Jose Mercury News covered the trend towards smart sprinkler controls. Smart sprinkler controllers promise to reduce water use for most users by over 30%.</p>
<p>Now the definition of a smart controller varies.  Options stretch from the addition of a rain sensor, with many devices offering WiFi connectivity that allows them to access online weather information.</p>
<p>The Mercury News article also made an interesting observation:</p>
<p>Indeed, when they first started rolling out, some of the devices actually resulted in residents increasing their water use, noted Peter Brostrom, water use efficiency program manager at the California Department of Water Resources. Those residents tended to be the ones who already were doing a good job of conserving water, he said.</p>
<p>&#8220;If you are already very conscientious with your water use, a smart controller would probably not save you water,&#8221; said Brostrom. Instead, he added, they&#8217;re most effective &#8220;for people who don&#8217;t touch them and don&#8217;t look at them, who run the same schedule throughout the year.&#8221;</p>
<p>The bottom line is that if you are already observing water-saving practices by adjusting your irrigation controller as the weather changes, you’re unlikely to save water by changing out your controller. I’ve heard stories about a similar situation with the Nest thermostat.</p>
<p>Water savings are possible but, since the sprinklers and pipes-in-the-ground don’t change, much of the water waste continues even with a smart controller.</p>
<p>Real savings require re-engineering the entire irrigation (or air-conditioning) system, pipes, sprinklers and all. Until that happens, water saving claims should be considered with some skepticism.</p>
<p>Link to news article: <a href="http://www.mercurynews.com/troy-wolverton/ci_28761569/wolverton-dreaming-smart-sprinkler-system-my-dumb-home">http://www.mercurynews.com/troy-wolverton/ci_28761569/wolverton-dreaming-smart-sprinkler-system-my-dumb-home</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../2015/06/04/do-smart-sprinkler-controllers-save-water/index.html">Do Smart Sprinkler Controllers Save Water?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">Revely Microsystems</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
